Today was a very great day for all of you
to jump in the river and enjoy yourselves very much.
I remember the past
of such days which I have also enjoyed before.
But one must know that
it’s not the outside that really gives you pleasure; it’s the inside.
Whether there is outside or not,
inside should be so elated.
You can use this as a memory  for yourself,
whenever you feel dejected or depressed,
and should try to maintain that
moment of joy and happiness within yourself.
I hope you were in the present at that time,
so that it is completely recorded in your memory
and that you will enjoy all that.
The sign of a good Sahaja yogi is that
he has no complaints.
He doesn’t give ideas, suggestions,
and object to what Mother says
and give new dimensions to it,
doesn’t argue and thirdly, he’s always enjoying.
If you are not enjoying still your eyes are moving on one side,
brain on another side, your ears in the third direction
then you are not integrated. You are not yet a proper Sahaja yogi.
So you have to be a very proper, sensible Sahaja yogi.
In your ascent you will discover all these things.
So try to be more in the center, in the present,
and then only this will become
a prominent feature within your heart.
And on that will be seated your Spirit shining all the time.
But the seat of the Spirit is  all the time wobbly
and is not there;
so Spirit does not know how to emit light in your life.
Now what I find is that our attention
goes to all kinds of various activities,
which we should see like the sea that was flowing.
The re was lots of stones there.
And one can learn a lesson from that,  that when the stones
are there it makes a ripple, a sound, a reflection back,
and the water is obstructed.
In the same way, if we have stones in our head,
that the flow of Kundalini get obstructed
and then we get all kinds of, you see, reflections
and we reflect back and then we try
to give some suggestions or things, all that.
We don’t allow the flow to go
straight forward in a very smooth manner.
So also it is very interesting and it makes a,
you feel more interested because it helps the ego
to grow more.
But one has to learn that  that’s not the temperament of a Sahaja yogi.
Sahaja yogi is a subtle personality,
absolutely peaceful within himself.
Người đó không phàn nàn về bất cứ điều gì.
Người đó luôn thưởng thức. Người đó không nói bất cứ điều gì.
Người đó không khóc lóc. Người đó không than khóc.
Người đó không nói: “Cái này sai. Cái kia sai”.
Người đó không nói về gia đình mình,
con cái, họ hàng của mình. Người đó không làm thế.
Và nếu người đó phải nói về ai đó, người đó luôn nói những điều tốt đẹp,
không nói điều xấu. Ngoại trừ các nhóm trưởng; khi Ta hỏi họ,
họ phải nói cho Ta sự thật,
nếu Ta hỏi hoặc nếu Ta biết điều gì đó hoặc nếu Ta phải xác minh.
Nhưng các con không nên quá dính mắc vào gia đình mình, 'mẹ tôi',
chị em, vợ, chồng, cái này, cái kia.
Giờ là lúc để các con vươn lên.
Những ai sẽ vươn lên và vượt qua điều đó sẽ là một ý tưởng hay.
Thứ hai, như Ta đã nói với các con,
rằng niềm vui của phương Tây đã kết thúc bởi vì
đàn ông đã đánh mất sức mạnh của đàn ông,
và phụ nữ đã đánh mất sức mạnh của phụ nữ.
Nó giống như đôi mắt đi vào vị trí của cái mũi
và cái mũi ở vị trí của đôi mắt.
Đó là lý do tại sao sự đặt sai vị trí này đã diễn ra.
Vì vậy, hãy cố gắng thưởng thức vai trò mà các con có, các con đã đảm nhận
và đừng thực hiện vai trò của người khác.
Đây là một điều rất đơn giản mà người ta nên chấp nhận
và nên giải quyết nó. Và Ta chắc chắn rằng
tất cả chúng ta sẽ đạt được sự cân bằng và chúng ta sẽ ở trung tâm.
Bây giờ vấn đề rất đơn giản
là chúng ta phải chấp nhận hiện tại, giây phút hiện tại.
Nó rất đơn giản. Tại giây phút hiện tại này
các con đang ngồi đây trước mặt Ta để dự Lễ Puja.
Tại mỗi giây phút hiện tại là để được thưởng thức.
Mỗi giây phút hiện tại là để được thưởng thức.
Không lo lắng về tương lai.
Không buồn phiền về quá khứ.
Lòng trắc ẩn của Thượng đế là to lớn; to lớn.
Hãy để Ngài giải quyết việc đó.
Khi các con cố gắng đóng vai trò của mình thì lòng trắc ẩn, như Ta đã nói với các con,
tác động lên những viên đá
và những viên đá tạo ra tất cả những gợn sóng và âm thanh và tất cả sự
lộn xộn này. Vì vậy, cách tốt nhất để cho phép tâm trí
được ổn thỏa, là hãy bình an, tỉnh thức tỉnh thức, không buồn ngủ.
Chỉ khi các con ngủ, thì các con mới không có những viên đá ở đó.
Vì vậy khi các con tỉnh thức, hãy quan sát và thưởng thức từng khoảnh khắc.
Đây là thông điệp cho ngày hôm nay,
bởi vì thời gian thực sự rất đẹp
và Ta nghĩ tốt hơn là các con hãy ở trong nhận thức không suy nghĩ và thưởng thức.
[Mẹ tiếp tục bằng tiếng Hindi.]